pirate4x4.com 2001-06-30

# Pirate4x4.Com - Privacy Statement

**Pirate4x4.Com Privacy Statement **

This privacy statement discloses our privacy practices for the website located at [http://www.pirate4x4.com](http://www.pirate4x4.com/). This web site has agreed to the following;

**Information Collection and Use**  
Pirate4x4.Com (we) are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. We may collect information from our users at several different points on our website. 

**Registration**  
In order to fully use and access all parts of this website, a user (you) must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as occupation and vehicle). 

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in **no way linked to any personally identifiable information** while on our site. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. Future business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to, or control over these cookies. 

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

**Newsletter**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. 

**Surveys & Contests**  
Our website requests information from users via surveys and/or for contests. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. All information submitted must be correct or that person will be disqualified. 

**Security**  
This website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line. Online, our security policy is that only those people who have a need to know have access to the database, and a security policy is in place to prevent any unauthorized people from using this database. The security policy is addressed and discussed in weekly meetings with the applicable employees. Employees can only obtain access to database information through password protected means. If and when our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with encryption software. While on a secure page, such as an order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just 'surfing'. If and when we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to your information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers' information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure 24/7 monitored environment, protected by a lock, a security system and an alarm system that automatically notifies a security service if tampered with. If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to us at our contact web page. 

**Children's Online Privacy**  
If this web site pertains mainly to children under the age of 13, there will be a mechanism to collect age information and to obtain parental consent for the use of the website by the child. If parental consent is not granted, access to that child will be blocked, per (COPPA). 

**Special Offers**  
We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members may occasionally receive information on critical trail closuers, etc. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our choice and opt-out below. 

**Correction/Updating Personal Information:**  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we do offer a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to us. This can usually be done at the member information page or by emailing us at our contact web page, where we offer email, and possibly mail and/or telephone methods of contact. 

**Choice/Opt-out**   
Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information. Users who no longer wish to receive email from us may opt-out of receiving these communications by changing it in their profile. 

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will email those changes in a communication to all members, so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

**Advertising**  
Pirate4x4.Com works with a third party that serves ads to this site. To find out more about how Engage Media manages the privacy of information in conjunction with serving ads on this site, please go to <http://www.flycast.com/about_us/about-privacy.html>. 

**Contact Us**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or about your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:
